Jinbin Hu | Curriculum Vitae

Department of CSE, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Hong Kong SAR – China

 \square +86-15274826560 • \square jinbinhu@ust.hk

I am currently a Post-doctoral from Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong SAR, advised by Prof. Kai Chen. My current research centers on transport protocols and load balancing for large-scale datacenter networks, RDMA networking, learning-based network systems, privacy-preserving computing, and programmable switching architectures*.

Education

PostDoc, Dept. of CSE, HKUST Hong Kong SAR Computer Science and Engineering 1.2022-Advisor: Prof. Kai Chen. Ph.D., School of Computer Science & Engineering, Central South University Changsha, China 9.2016-12.2020 Computer Science and Technology Advisor: Prof. Jiawei Huang. M.S., School of Electronic & Information Engineering, Beijing Jiaotong University Beijing, China Microelectronics and Solid State Electronics 9.2008-1.2011 Advisor: Prof. Xiaoguang Li. B.S., School of Electronic & Information Engineering, Beijing Jiaotong University Beijing, China Electronic Science and Technology 9.2004-7.2008

Experiences

0	Changsha University of Science & Technology Lecturer	Changsha, China 12.2021-
	Teaching and researching in School of Computer and Communication Engineering.	
0	Hunan Mechanical & Electrical Polytechnic Engineer	Changsha, China 8.2014–12.2021
	Teaching and researching in School of Electrical Engineering.	
0	National University of Defense Technology FPGA Verification Engineer	Changsha, China 8.2013-8.2014
	Responsible for FPGA verification of multi-core CPU in Microelectronics Institute.	
0	Empyrean Technology Co., Ltd IC Software Test Engineer Responsible for IC simulation software testing.	Beijing, China 1.2011-8.2013

^{*}Last Updated Jan. 2022

Publications

1.	Load Balancing in PFC-Enabled Datacenter Networks Jinbin Hu, Chaoliang Zeng, Zilong Wang, Hong Xu, Jiawei Huang, Kai Chen. In Proc. ACM APNet, 2022.	7.2022
2.	RPO: Receiver-driven Transport Protocol Using Opportunistic Transmission in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Zhaoyi Li, Yijun Li, Wenchao Jiang, Kai Chen, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. IEEE ICNP, 2021. (CCF B)	11.2021
3.	Adjusting Switching Granularity of Load Balancing for Heterogeneous Datacenter Traffic Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang*, Wenjun Lv, Weihe Li, Zhaoyi Li, Wenchao Jiang, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, 2021, 29(5): 2367-2384. (CCF A)	6.2021
4.	AMRT: Anti-ECN Marking to Improve Utilization of Receiver-driven Transmission in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Zhaoyi Li, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. ACM ICPP, 2020. (CCF B)	8.2020
5.	CAPS: Coding-based Adaptive Packet Spraying to Reduce Flow Completion Time in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang*, Wenjun Lv, Yutao Zhou, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, 2019, 27(6): 2338-2353. (CCF A)	10.2019
6.	TLB: Traffic-aware Load Balancing with Adaptive Granularity in Data Center Networks Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Wenjun Lv, Weihe Li, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. ACM ICPP, 2019. (CCF B)	8.2019
7.	CAPS: Coding-based Adaptive Packet Spraying to Reduce Flow Completion Time in Data Center Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Wenjun Lv, Yutao Zhou, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. IEEE INFOCOM, 2018. (CCF A)	4.2018
(*	stands for Corresponding author.)	

Research Project

o The National Natural Science Foundation of China

Study on Transport Control in Data Center Lossless Network Based on Priority-based Flow Control, 2022.1.1-2024.12.31. (PI)

o The Natural Science Foundation of Hunan Province

Study on Communication Optimization Technology for Distributed Deep Neural Network, 2022.1.1-2024.12.31. (PI)